One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Huh? Rain?
Ha? Yağmur mu?
This doesn't feel like rain.
Yağmur gibi durmuyor.
Is it hail?
Dolu mu?
No. There's something falling...
Hayır. Bir şey düşüyor...
– What?!
– Ne?!
Why the Log Pose is Spherical
Seyir Pusulası Neden Yukarıyı Gösteriyor?
Hold on tight!
Sıkı tutunun!
Don't fall off the ship!
Tutunacak bir şey bulun!
What? What?! What's happening?!
Ne? Ne?! Ne oluyor?!
A dream! Yeah, this must be a dream!
Rüya! Evet bu bir rüya olmalı!
A dream?! Oh, thank–
Rüya mı?! Ah şükürler–
Hey, there's still more coming!
Hey, dahası geliyor!
Watch out!
Dikkat edin!
Quick, turn the ship around!
Gemiyi ters yöne döndürün, çabuk!
What, in these waves?!
Ne, bu dalgalarda mı?!
Luffy, protect the ship! She won't survive!
Luffy, gemiyi koru! Bu gidişle dayanamaz!
On it!
Hallediyorum!
Hm... Usopp?
Hm... Usopp?
There's nothing to fear.
Korkacak bir şey yok!
Just breathe in and close your eyes.
Gözlerini kapat ve sadece nefes al.
Now, slowly open them again...
Şimdi, yavaşça gözlerini aç...
and watch all your worries disapp–
ve tüm endişelerinin gitmiş olduğunu–
A skeleton!
İskelet!
Hey! Don't throw it at me!
Hey! Bana doğru atmasana!
There's still more debris!
Hâlâ enkaz düşüyor!
A skeleton!
İskelet!
I said don't throw it at me!
Bana doğru atma diyorum!
Why would a ship fall out of the sky?
Gökten niye gemi enkazı düşer ki?
It doesn't make sense.
Çok garip.
There's nothing in the sky.
Gökyüzünde hiçbir şey yok.
Th-The Grand Line sure is a scary place.
G-Grand Line gerçekten korkunç bir yer.
What is it, Nami?
Ne oldu, Nami-san?
This is bad!
Çok fena!
The log pose is broken.
Seyir pusulası bozuldu.
It's stuck pointing up.
Yukarıya saplanıp kaldı.
It's not broken.
Bozuk değil.
Its log has been overwritten by an island with a stronger magnetic field.
Daha güçlü manyetik alana sahip bir adanın etkisinde.
What?!
Ne?!
If it's pointing upwards,
Yukarıyı gösteriyorsa,
that means an island in the sky has taken hold of it.
bir gökyüzü adasının etkisinde demektir.
– An island in the sky?!
– Gökyüzü adası mı?!
What even is that?
O ne ki?
You're saying islands can float?
Havada uçan adalar mı var?
A-And that ship and the skeleton fell down from there?
V-Ve o gemi ve iskeletler oradan mı düştü?
I can't see a thing in the sky, island or otherwise.
Gökyüzünde ada falan göremiyorum.
It's not so cut and dry.
Tam olarak öyle değil.
It's more accurate to say that it's a floating sea.
Aslında gökyüzünde süzülen bir deniz demek daha doğru.
A sea?
Deniz mi?
It's just getting more confusing.
Gittikçe daha da karmaşık oluyor.
Awesome! So there's a sea floating in the sky with an island on it!
Vay! Yani deniz gökyüzünde süzülüyor ve üstünde bir ada mı var?!
Alright! We're going!
Tamamdır, gidiyoruz!
Men! Set a course straight upward!
Millet, rotamız gökyüzü!
Up full rudder!
Pruvayı kaldırın! Pruva: Geminin ön tarafı, baş kısmı.
Just how do you plan to sail upward, Captain?
Gökyüzüne nasıl gitmeyi planlıyorsun, kaptan?
To be honest, I don't know much about any sky island,
Açıkçası, herhangi bir gökyüzü adası hakkında çok bir şey bilmiyorum,
nor have I ever seen one.
üstelik hiç görmedim de.
Of course you haven't! There's no way islands or seas could float in the sky!
Tabii ki görmedin! Gökyüzünde deniz de ada da olmaz!
The log pose is just broken.
Seyir pusulası bozuldu, o kadar.
No, Miss Navigator.
Hayır, Rotacı hanım.
What you should be worrying about now is not your log pose.
Endişelenmeniz gereken seyir pusulanız değil...
It's how to get to the sky.
gökyüzüne nasıl gideceğiniz.
No matter what bizarre circumstance befalls your ship, or what danger it descends into,
Geminize ne olursa olsun, hangi tehlikeli duruma düşerse düşsün,
you must never doubt your log pose.
seyir pusulanızdan şüphe etmemelisin.
This is an ironclad rule.
Bu temel kuraldır.
In these seas, it's your own common sense that you should doubt more than anything.
Bu denizlerde asıl kuşku duymanız gereken sağduyunuzdur.
Wherever the needle points, there's guaranteed to be an island.
İbrenin gösterdiği yönde kuşkusuz bir ada var.
What did she have to open the coffin for?
İlla tabutu açması mı gerekiyordu?
Find anything out?
Bir şey bulabildin mi?
We'll see.
Bakacağız.
This is quite tasteless, you know!
Ölüye biraz saygın olsun ya!
A beauty handling human remains is surprisingly alluring.
İnsan kalıntılarını işleyen bir güzellik şaşırtı derecede alımlı.
Hm? Where's Luffy?
Hm? Luffy nerede?
Jump, Luffy!
Zıpla, Luffy!
What are they up to this time?
Yine ne yapıyorlar?
Exploring, they said.
Keşif, dediler.
Ah, it's fully restored.
Ah, tamamlandı.
These holes right here are man-made.
Gördüğünüz delikler, insan eliyle yapılmış.
Oh, so this person died after being stabbed in the head.
O hâlde bu insan, kafasından bıçaklanarak ölmüş.
Actually, they're the result of a medical procedure.
Aslında bakarsan, bu bir tıbbi işlemin sonucu.
It's called trepanation, isn't it, Doctor?
Trepanasyon deniyor, değil mi doktor?
That's right. The technique of drilling holes into the skull to treat brain tumors.
Doğru. Kafatasına delik açarak beyin tümörlerini tedavi etmeye yönelik bir işlem.
But that practice hasn't been used for centuries!
Ama okuduğuma göre bu yüzyıllardır uygulanmıyor!
Exactly. This man died over 200 years ago.
Evet. Bu adam, 200 yılı aşkın bir süre önce ölmüş.
He was in his early thirties.
Otuzlu yaşlarının başlarındayımş.
He died after falling ill at sea.
Denizde hastalanıp ölmüş.
Compared to his other bones, his teeth were very well preserved...
Katran ile kaplandığı için diğer kemiklerine kıyasla...
as they had been painted with tar.
dişleri iyi korunmuş.
Since this custom is unique to a particular region in the South Blue,
Bu gelenek, Güney Mavi'nin özel bir bölgesine ait olduğu için...
history suggests that this vessel was originally an expedition ship.
diyebiliriz ki bu gemi bir keşif gemisiymiş.
There it is. The Saint Briss of the South Blue's Kingdom of Briss.
İşte burada. Güney Mavi'nin Briss Krallığı'ndan Aziz Briss.
It set out 208 years ago.
208 yıl önce yola çıkmış.
It looks just like the falling ship.
Aynı düşen gemiye benziyor.
Yeah, it did have the same emblem too.
Evet, aynı amblem onda da vardı.
So for over 200 years, this ship has been wandering the skies.
Yani, bu gemi 200 yılı aşkın süredir gökyüzünde dolaşıyordu.
Can you really deduce all these things from a skeleton?
Bütün bu çıkarımları bir iskeletten mi yaptın?
Though corpses do not talk, they do tell plenty of tales.
Ölüler konuşamasa bile pek çok şey anlatabilirler.
An expedition ship like this should contain plenty of records detailing its journey.
Bu tür bir keşif gemisinde, yolculuklarıyla ilgili detaylı kayıtlar bulunur.
Sure, but the ship's sunk into–
Evet ama gemi–
You guys! What are you doing?!
Çocuklar! Ne yapıyorsunuz?!
Luffy! Grab my hand!
Luffy! Elimi tut!
Help me!
Yardım edin!
Everyone, check it out!
Hey, baksanıza!
We did it!
Başardık!
We found something really cool!
Aşırı havalı bir şey bulduk!
Look at this!
Şuna bakın!
– A map of the sky island?!
– Gökyüzü adası haritası mı?!
"Skypiea."
"Skypiea."
Right? Right?
Öyle mi? Öyle mi?
So there really is an island in the sky?!
Yani gerçekten bir gökyüzü adası var, ha?!
– Yahoo!
– Oley!
Hooray! There really is a sky island!
Yaşasın! Gökyüzü adası gerçek!
It's a dream island! We can go to a dream island!
Bir düşler adası! Düşler adasına gideceğiz!
– Dream island!
– Düşler adası!
You're getting too excited! This is nothing more than a possibility.
Gaza gelmeyin! Kesin olarak bir şey bilmiyoruz.
There are a lot of fake maps in the world.
Ortalıkta dolaşan bir sürü sahte harita var.
Ah, sorry! But this one's real! I'm sure it's real!
Ah, üzgünüm! Ama bu gerçek olan! Eminim gerçektir!
But listen!
Ama dinle, Luffy!
I'm saying that we have no way of getting there!
Oraya gitmemizin imkânı yok!
Hey, Nami...
Hey, Nami...
Please be careful with the ship.
Lütfen, gemiye karşı nazik ol.
You're a navigator! Figure it out!
Sen rotacımızsın! Bir yolunu bul!
Please?
Lütfen?
"Figure it out"?! Do you think it's that easy?!
"Bir yolunu bul" mu?! O kadar kolay mı sanıyorsun?!
Nami's so cute when she's angry.
Nami-san sinirlenince ne kadar da tatlı oluyor.
I don't care! I wanna go to the sky!
Banane! Gökyüzüne gitmek istiyorum!
This is getting us nowhere!
Böyle bir yere varamayız!
In any case, we can't keep sailing like this.
Her halükârda, böyle hiçbir yere gidemeyiz.
Robin's right that we need more information.
Robin'in dediği gibi daha fazla bilgiye ihtiyacımız var.
If that huge ship really was in the sky,
Eğer o devasa gemi gerçekten gökyüzündeydi ise,
there must be some way for the Merry to go there too.
Merry'nin de oraya gitmesinin bir yolu olmalı.
Let's try to retrieve whatever records are left on the wreck.
Enkazdan toplayabildiğimiz kadar ipucu toplayalım.
But, that ship is completely sunk by now.
Ama gemi tamamen battı.
If it's sunk, then we need to salvage it!
Battıysa da gider kurtarırız!
– Alright!
– Pekâlâ!
How, exactly?!
Sanki yapabileceksiniz!
What's "salvage"?
Ne demek istiyorlar?
It's the process of lifting a sunken ship back up.
Batan bir gemiyi yüzeye çıkarmak.
But it's no use with that ship. It's too big.
Ama o gemi çıkmaz, çok büyük.
Well, well, well...
Peki, peki, peki...
You're really making us do something crazy here.
Bizi gerçekten delice bir işe sürüklüyorsun!
Yeah.
Evet.
Nami my sweet!
Nami-swan!
I'll be sure to find you some clues on how to get to the sky!
Gökyüzüne gitmenin bir yolunu bulacağıma söz veriyorum!
I'm counting on it.
Sana güveniyorum.
Don't worry about a thing! My design is impeccable!
Endişelenmeyin! Mühendisliğim kusursuzdur!
And with that...
Öyleyse...
good luck!
bol şans!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, hey, hey!
Chopper here. Everyone, report in!
Ben Chopper. Herkes durumunu bildirsin!
Luffy here. There's a bunch of monsters down here. Over!
Luffy bildiriyor. Burada bir sürü canavar var. Tamam!
Is this a nest of giant sea snakes?
Burası dev deniz yılanlarının yuvası mı?
Sanji here. Ahh, it's looking this way!
Sanji bildiriyor. Ahh, buraya bakıyor!
Okay.
Tamam.
That's it?!
"Tamam" mı?!
Don't worry, I'm sure they'll manage somehow!
Endişelenme, bir şekilde halledeceklerdir!
Chopper, keep the brake at the ready.
Chopper, frene basmaya hazır ol!
Got it.
Anlaşıldı.
Phew... Good thing I didn't go with them.
Aman aman... İyi ki onlarla birlikte gitmedim.
♪ Salvage! Salvage! Salvage! ♪
♪ Enkaz! Enkaz! Enkaz! ♪
What in the world...?
Ne oluyor be...?
♪ Salvage! ♪
♪ Enkaz! ♪
♪ Salvage! Salvage! ♪
♪ Enkaz! Enkaz! ♪
Halt!
Durun!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
This is where that ship sank?
Burası geminin battığı yer mi?
– Aye aye, sir! Boss!
– Evet, patron!
And that boss... would be me!
Ve o patron... Benim!
"Salvage King" Masira Masira Pirates Bounty: 23 Million Belly
"Enkaz Kralı" Masira Masira Korsanları Kaptanı Kelle Ödülü: 23 Milyon Beli
Prepare to pull her up!
Çıkarmaya hazırlanın!
This sunken ship now belongs to me,
Bu batık gemi artık bana,
Salvage King Masira!
Enkaz Kralı, Masira'ya ait!
A group of weirdos just had to show up right now.
Yine soytarı kılıklılar buldu bizi.
You, right there! What do you think you're doing?
Siz oradakiler! Ne yaptığınızı sanıyorsunuz?
These are my waters!
Buralar benim sularım!
Your waters?
Senin suların mı?
That's right.
Aynen öyle.
Any ship that sinks in this area belongs to me!
Burada batan her gemi bana aittir!
You twerps had better not have touched that ship yet!
Siz salaklar umarım o gemiye dokunmamışsınızdır!
It appears that person is planning to salvage the ship.
Görünüşe göre o kişi gemiyi kurtarmayı planlıyor.
Yeah, they mentioned that once or twice.
Evet, birkaç kez belirtti.
So what do we do? Maybe this is a good thing?
Peki ne yapacağız? Şans yüzümüze gülmüş olabilir.
Stop that blabbering!
Kendi aranızda konuşmayı kesin!
Answer my question this instant!
Hemen soruma cevap verin!
Excuse me! Could I ask you a question?
Pardon! Bir soru sorabilir miyim?
You're asking now?!
Soru mu soracaksın?!
Very well. Ask me whatever you want.
Pekâlâ. Sor bakalım.
Are you salvaging that ship to scrape up some loot?
Bayım, gemiyi kurtarmaya mı çalışıyorsunuz?
"Ape-some"?
"Kurtarmak" mı?
Did you just call me ape-some?
Bana kahraman mı demeye çalışıyorsun?
An ape that's handsome. Is that what you think?
Yani o kadar yakışıklı mıyım?
Sure!
Evet!
Ah, I don't know what to say!
Ah, ne diyeceğimi bilemiyorum!
I don't think that's a real word.
Öyle dediğini hiç sanmıyorum.
So, are you gonna salvage it?!
Yani enkazı çıkaracak mısınız?!
Well, let's just say this: if a ship sinks, I unsink it!
Evet, eğer batmış bir gemi varsa ben çıkarırım!
That's the kind of guy I am.
İşte böyle bir adamım.
I'll even sink a ship just so I can salvage it!
Gerekirse enkazını çıkarmak için gemi batırırım.
There's no ship I can't pull to the surface!
Yüzeye çıkaramayacağım gemi yok!
Then, do you mind if we watch you at your craft?
Peki seni izleyip feyzalmamıza müsaade eder misin?
Hm? Oh, have you never seen a salvage before?
Ne? Daha önce enkaz çıkarılmasını izlemediniz mi?
Sure, then! Watch and learn!
Peki, öyle olsun! İzleyin ve öğrenin!
Good! For now, let's just wait and see what he does.
Güzel! Şimdilik bekleyip yapacaklarını izleyelim.
W-Watch out...
D-Dikkat edin...
Boss, there's trouble!
Patron, bir sorunumuz var!
What is it?!
Ne oldu?!
The crew that dove down to set up the cradle–
Sistemi kurmaya inen ekip–
Did they run into a sea king?
Deniz kralına mı denk geldiler?
No... they look like they got beat up by someone.
Hayır... biri onları dövmüş gibi duruyor.
What?! So there's somebody else down there?
Ne?! O zaman bizden önce inen başkası mı var?
Those three...
Bizimkiler...
Uh-oh...
Eyvah eyvah...
Then...
O hâlde...
Hey, you bunch!
Hey, siz!
Ah, well, that...
Ha, evet...
There's someone down there! Be careful!
Aşağıda bizden başkaları var! Dikkatli olun!
Y-Yeah!
T-Tamam!
– Good. He's an idiot.
– Şanslıyız ki aptal.
Men!
Millet!
Hurry up and set the cradle!
Hemen gemi kızağını hazırlayın!
We're commencing the salvage!
Çıkarmaya başlıyoruz!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Başüstüne!
He's waving at us.
Bize el sallıyor.
We're screwed if he notices the air hose.
Hava borularını farkederse bittik demektir!
Yeah, I know...
Evet, b-biliyorum...
Listen, men!
Dinleyin beni!
Just imagine them naked!
Çocuk oyuncağıymış gibi davranın!
They're watching us now...
İzlendiğimiz için...
but we shouldn't be getting nervous!
gerilmeyin!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
Lower the cradle!
Kızağı indirin!
Watch out for whomever's down there!
Aşağıdaki kimse, ona dikkat edin!
Aye aye, sir!
Hayhay efendim!
He seems to really take pride in this.
Bu işi ne kadar da ciddiye alıyor.
It feels like he's trying to impress us.
Sanki bizi etkilemek istiyor gibi.
Don't just stand there!
Öyle dikilmeyin!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
Hey!
Hey!
Look.
Bakın.
The cradle is set and secure!
Kızak hazır ve nazır!
What's–
Bu da ne–
Wh-Wh-
B-Bu–
What's that? A monkey?
Bu da ne? Maymun mu?
What's that monkey?
O maymun ne için?
Ah, this?
Ah, bu mu?
You have a good eye.
Gözlerin keskinmiş.
That's not any old bow.
Bu, sıradan bir pruva değil.
Launch...
Hazırlayın...
the Barco Hunter!
Barco Hunter'ı!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
Monkey,
Maymun,
Monkey, monkey,
Maymun, maymun,
Monkey, monkey, monkey!
Maymun, maymun, maymun!
Monkey,
Maymun,
Monkey, monkey,
Maymun, maymun,
Monkey, monkey, monkey!
Maymun, maymun, maymun!
Monkey,
Maymun,
Monkey, monkey,
Maymun, maymun,
Monkey, monkey, monkey!
Maymun, maymun, maymun!
Monkey,
Maymun,
Monkey, monkey,
Maymun, maymun,
Monkey, monkey, monkey!
Maymun, maymun, maymun!
Whoa!
Vay!
Wow! That's amazing!
Vay! Bu muhteşem!
It's so cool!
Çok havalı!
It is?
Öyle mi?
Forty meters to target.
40 metreye iniyoruz.
Thirty meters.
30 metre.
Twenty.
20.
Ten.
10.
Barco Hunter Joint:
Barco Hunter Bağlantısı:
Complete!
Tamamlandı!
Alright!
Pekâlâ!
Start blowing!
Üflemeye hazırlanın!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
A-Are they really...
G-Gerçekten...
planning to lift it up by blowing in air?
üfleyerek mi çıkartacaklar?
Are they serious?
Ciddi mi bunlar?
An air bubble?
Hava balonu mu?
The ship's started to float!
Gemi yükseliyor!
Go! Pull it up!
Hadi! Çekin yukarı!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
Keep the air supply steady!
Hava akışına devam edin!
Boss!
Patron!
Our underwater crew!
Su altı tayfası!
What is it?!
Ne oldu?!
What happened, my dear underlings?
Ne oldu, canım adamlarım?
There's someone inside the ship!
Geminin içinde biri var!
How dare you attack my underlings, whoever you are!
Her kimsen, adamlarıma saldırmaya nasıl cüret edersin!
How dare you!
Nasıl?!!
O-Oh, we're not planning on taking pictures or anything.
O-Oh, fotoğraf falan çekmeyecektik aslında.
You're not?!
Ne?!
Was he posing for a photo?
Bizim için poz mu veriyordu?
Boss! Help us!
Patron! Yardım et!
I'm going down there!
Aşağı iniyorum!
Continue pulling up the ship!
Gemiyi çekmeye devam edin!
– Aye aye, sir!
– Hayhay efendim!
Monkey Punch!
Maymun Yumruğu!
There it is.
Geliyor...
See? We don't need the barrels anymore.
Gördünüz mü? Artık fıçılara ihtiyacımız yok.
Nice of them to pump in so much air for us.
İçeri bu kadar hava pompalamış olmaları çok iyi.
But who would even be trying to pull up this ship?
Kim bu gemiyi yukarı çekiyor merak ediyorum?
I'm starting to think something happened to Nami and Robin.
Nami-san ve Robin-chan'a bir şey mi oldu acaba?
They're not responding to any of our calls!
Çağrılarımıza cevap vermiyorlar!
Who are you...
Siz kimsiniz,
raising hell in my waters?!
benim sularımda olay çıkarıyorsunuz?!
Huh?
Ha?
Ah... some ape.
Ah... bir maymun.
You think I'm that ape-some?
Ha? Sence kaslı mıyım?
Yeah, you're pretty apey.
Bir maymuna göre fena değilsin.
What's up with those words?
Ne diyorsunuz?
What words?
Ne mi?
Anyway, who are you?
Her neyse, sen kimsin?
Ah, I don't know what to say.
Ah, ne diyeceğimi bilmiyorum.
Do you really think so? You've got a great eye.
Gerçekten öyle mi düşünüyorsun? Gözlerin keskinmiş.
Just tell us who you are already!
Kimsin onu soruyoruz!
Um, I think there's something...
Aa, galiba bir şey...
Y-Yeah, there's something else under the ship!
E-Evet, geminin altında bir şey var!
Oh, so you came from the East Blue!
Oh, demek Doğu Mavi'den geliyorsunuz!
That's right! But, you know, you really are like a monkey!
Evet! Gerçekten maymuna benziyorsun!
Oh, you're too kind!
Oh, çok naziksin!
Well–
Şey–
What is that?! What the hell?!
Bu da ne?! Ne oluyor lan?!